Mohammed Abdulsalam

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: moha4mach@gmail.com | Mobile: +20 12 1165 0982

Location: Alexandria, Egypt

BACK END DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled back-end devleoper with over 2 year of experience in PHP, MySQL. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as Laravel. I worked on several projects using native PHP and MySQL/MariaDB, and have experience designing REST APIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

: PHP, SQL, Javascript, TeX Languages

Frameworks : Laravel, PHPUnit

Libraries : laravel-websockets, laravel-medialibrary, laravel-echo

: MySQL, MariaDB, SQLlite **Databases**

: OOP, MVC, HMVC, Regular Expressions, Accessibility (WCAG), REST, ERD Design, SRS Design Concepts

Dev Tools : Vim, XDebug, Vite, Git, Github Actions, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, cron, Docker

EXPERIENCE

Back End Developer Feb 2022 - Present

Freelance

- Desing and development of back-ends using PHP, MYSQL/MariaDB
- · Worked on REST APIs for medium-sized systems
- Analysis of stakeholders reuirements, and design ERD, SRS, and various documents
- Deployed and maintained websites on AWS EC2 linux server

Vice Head of Web Development Committee

Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

GDSC KSU

Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Share knowledge and experience with my fellow members
- Make sure the plan is suitable for members
- · Demonstrated critical topics in core Front End technologies, including SEO, and Accessibility, through number of sessions

EDUCATION

University of Kafrelsheikh - Faculty of Computers and Information

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.25/4

Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt Sep 2020 - Jul 2024

PROJECTS

Online Chat Demo Private

PHP, Laravel, HMVC, SCSS

Online customer service chat written in PHP / Laravel. Build with HMVC architectural pattern

- Utilized laravel-websockets & laravel-echo to provide real time communication
- Used laravel-medialibrary to facilitate media storing and retrieval
- Developed REST API for clients, and chat frontend using Blade and Javascript

Bookopia Demo PHP, Laravel, MVC, SCSS Source Code

- · A library management system written in PHP / Laravel. Build with MVC architectural pattern
- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, and SCSS
- Utilized Laravel Components to enhance the modularity of the frontend

• Extended **Blade** funcionality by writing customized **Directives**, that help us write less code

Salem Clinic WebsitePHP, MySQL, Javascript, Git
Private

- · Designed and developed dynamic monolith website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Worked on admin panel providing article management, content management, and admins priviliges
- Developed Markup to HTML library using PHP, and Javascript, utilized in articles creation, editing, and viewing
- Deployed using Apache server on AWS EC2 instance, with domain name and HTTPS certificate configured
- Used a cronjob to backup data periodically

Clinic Management System (ERP)

PHP, MariaDB, Socket.IO

Private

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with PHP
- Analysed stakeholders requirements, deigned **ERD** based on this analysis
- Used **XDebug** to facilitate debugging process, and **PHPUnit** to automate unit testing
- Worked on many features that support bussiness logic, includes live queues, activity log, authorization rules and priviliges, payroll system, patient management system, etc...
- Used Socket.IO under Node.js to build socket server to maintain live queues data between clients

CERTIFICATIONS

• ITI - Web Development Using PHP (150 hrs.)